Finding aid to the Margaret Myers Dunn papers CA.MS.00392
Smith College Archives
Margaret Myers Dunn papers
1935-1959
Smith College Archives
Myers Dunn, Margaret
CA.MS.00392
3.125 linear feet (9 containers)
Margaret Myers Dunn is a Smith College Alumna, Class of 1937. This collection contains correspondence, ephemera, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Margaret Myers Dunn was born Margaret Pauline Myers on May 1, 1916 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. She, her younger sister Harriet (Class of 1941), and her older brothers Clay and Roy were born to Stewart Clay Myers and Augusta Huth Myers.
Myers Dunn attended the Winchester School in Pittsburgh, PA for her preparatory education and enrolled in Smith College in 1933. In 1937, she graduated with a B.A. in Biology and a minor in German. She traveled through Europe on graduation and later married Richard Byam Dunn at the end of 1938. Richard Dunn was a Williams College undergraduate who later attended Harvard Law and courted Margaret since 1935. They wrote frequent letters back and forth throughout their courtship, and during World War II while Richard was stationed on the USS Steinaker. Margaret remained at home in Newton, MA, dedicating her time to maintaining the household and raising their young family.
Together they had four children. According to the Smith Alumnae Quarterly (Summer 2004), they spent much of their life in the Boston area where Margaret was "deeply involved in scouting and the PTA." Margaret went on to earn her Masters of Social Work from Boston College School of Social Work in 1965 and worked with the physically and intellectually challenged, including senior citizens (SAQ, Summer 2004). The family moved after the war to Wellesley, Massachusetts, and after Richard's retirement to Kimball Farms, in Lenox, MA. She died there on October 29, 2003. Richard died October 2, 2002.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes digital copies of the correspondence, physical copies of the transcribed correspondence, the original personal correspondence, photographs, ephemera and travel memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Margaret Myers Dunn papers were donated to the Smith College Archives by her daughter Erica H. Dunn in 2014.
Separated Materials
The collection also contains a 6-mm film titled "Graduation + alumnae parade 1937" and a DVD titled "Smith College graduation events 1937 and/or 1938". Please contact Smith College Archives for information on access and use.
Women college students -- Massachusetts -- Northampton; Women -- education (higher) -- Massachusetts -- History -- 20th Century; Courtship; correspondence; photographs; memorabilia; Myers, Margaret, 1916 - 2003; Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae -- History -- Sources; World War, 1939 - 1945; Williams College; Steinaker (Destroyer: DD-863)
- Series I: Transcripts
  - CD-ROMS: Correspondence Transcripts, 1935 - 1946 (Box 2106.2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Transcript, Volume 1, 1935 - 1937 (Box 2106.2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Transcript, Volume 2, 1938 (Box 2106.2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Transcript, Volume 3, 1944 - 1946 (Box 2106.2, Folder 4)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - May, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 5)
  - June, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 6)
  - July, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 7)
  - August, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 8)
  - September, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 9)
  - October, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 10)
  - November, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 11)
  - December, 1935 (Box 2106.3, Folder 12)
  - January, 1936 (Box 2106.3, Folder 13)
  - February, 1936 (Box 2106.3, Folder 14)
  - March, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 15)
  - April, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 16)
  - May, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 17)
  - June, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 18)
  - July, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 19)
  - August, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 20)
  - September, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 21)
  - October, 1936 (Box 2106.4, Folder 22)
  - November, 1936 (Box 2106.5, Folder 23)
  - December, 1936 (Box 2106.5, Folder 24)
  - January, 1937 (Box 2106.5, Folder 25)
  - February, 1937 (Box 2106.5, Folder 26)
  - March, 1937 (Box 2106.5, Folder 27)
  - April, 1937 (Box 2106.5, Folder 28)
  - May, 1937 (Box 2106.5, Folder 29)
  - June, 1937 (Box 2106.5, Folder 30)
  - July, 1937 (Box 2106.6, Folder 31)
  - August, 1937 (Box 2106.6, Folder 32)
  - September, 1937 (Box 2106.6, Folder 33)
  - October, 1937 (Box 2106.6, Folder 34)
  - November, 1937 (Box 2106.6, Folder 35)
  - December, 1937 (Box 2106.6, Folder 36)
  - January, 1938 (Box 2106.6, Folder 37)
  - February, 1938 (Box 2106.6, Folder 38)
  - March, 1938 (Box 2106.6, Folder 39)
  - April, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 40)
  - May, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 41)
  - June, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 42)
  - July, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 43)
  - August, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 44)
  - September, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 45)
  - October, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 46)
  - November, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 47)
  - December, 1938 (Box 2106.7, Folder 48)
  - January, 1939 (Box 2106.7, Folder 49)
  - September, 1939 (Box 2106.7, Folder 50)
  - May, 1940 (Box 2106.8, Folder 51)
  - June, 1940 (Box 2106.8, Folder 52)
  - February, 1941 (Box 2106.8, Folder 53)
  - December, 1941 (Box 2106.8, Folder 54)
  - June, 1944 (Box 2106.8, Folder 55)
  - July, 1944 (Box 2106.8, Folder 56)
  - August, 1944 (Box 2106.8, Folder 57)
  - April, 1945 (Box 2106.8, Folder 58)
  - May, 1945 (Box 2106.8, Folder 59)
  - June, 1945 (Box 2106.8, Folder 60)
  - July, 1945 (Box 2106.8, Folder 61)
  - August, 1945 (Box 2106.8, Folder 62)
  - September, 1945 (Box 2106.8, Folder 63)
  - October, 1945 (Box 2106.9, Folder 64)
  - November, 1945 (Box 2106.9, Folder 65)
  - December, 1945 (Box 2106.9, Folder 66)
  - February, 1946 (Box 2106.9, Folder 67)
  - March, 1946 (Box 2106.9, Folder 68)
  - April, 1954 (Box 2106.9, Folder 69)
  - September, 1959 (Box 2106.9, Folder 70)
  - various letters, 1941-1945 (Box 2106.9, Folder 71)
- Series III: Miscellaneous
  - Subseries a. Commencement ephemera, 1937 (Box 2106.10, Folder 72)
  - Subseries b. General ephemera, undated (Box 2106.10, Folder 73)
  - Subseries c. Travel, 1937 (Box 2106.10, Folder 74)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - (6) 5.5"4" photographic prints, "Various photographs"., 1935 (Box 2106.10, Folder 75)
  - (14) 2"3" photographic prints, "Scenes from Cape Cod". Note: See correspondence., 07/06/1935 (Box 2106.10)
  - (4) 2"3" (4) 4"2.5" photographic prints, "Portraits and scenes on boats". Note: See correspondence., 07/26/1936; 08/30/1936 (Box 2106.10)
  - (5) 3"4" photographic prints, "Photographs from 1937" (Box 2106.10)
  - (5) negatives, "Margaret and brother". Note: See correspondence., 1937 (Box 2106.10)
  - (12) 4"3" photographic prints, "Scenes from Gettysburg". Note: See correspondence., 1938 (Box 2106.10)
  - (1) 3"2" photographic print, "Dog"., 1938 (Box 2106.10)
  - (2) 3"2" photographic prints, "USS Steinaker"., 11/11/1945 (Box 2106.10)